hello students my name is Molly stone
Molly stone
my name is Molly stone this is my first
name this is my last name now here's the
question what is your name
what is your name my name is Molly stone
my name is Molly stone okay let's
practice what is your name my name is
Lisa Roberts what is your name my name
is Alex Roy what is your name my name is
Marty Pierre okay now this is my first
name new question what is your first
name what is your first name
new answer
my first name is Ollie my first name is
Molly okay was practice what is your
first name my first name is Lisa what is
your first name my first name is onion
what is your first name my first name is
Mary okay yeah this is my last name new
question what is your last name what is
your last name my last name is stone
my last name is stone okay
what is your last name my last name is
Roberts what is your last name - name is
Oxford what is your last name my last
name is Pierre Junction possession okay
now we're going to talk about position
all right
my my your your his his her her it's
it's
our our your your there there my my your
his her
it's our your there now these are
singular equals one these are plural
equals two plus okay now some examples
my name my name your name your name his
name his name her name her name its name
its name our name our name your name
your name their name their name now look
and listen and listen
my name is Molly stone my first name is
Molly
my last name is stone your name is Ollie
oxide your first name is Ollie your last
name is aqua
her name is Julia Roberts her first name
is Julia her last name is Roberts his
name is Tom Cruise
his first name is Tom his last name is
Cruz it's name is Dolly her name is
Peggy Stone her first name is Peggy her
last name is Stone our last name is
Stone
[Music]
now students here's the question what is
what is name name name is now let's
practice with some photos now muddy what
is her name her name is Madonna yes
Oh Lee what is his name his name is on
20 abundance now ollie
what is his first name his first name is
Antonia and are we what is his last name
his last name is Banderas yeah it's very
good
no Lisa what is his first name his first
name is Sean and Lisa what is his first
name it is Chris what is their last name
their last name is Penn yes no mommy
what is her name her name is Peggy what
is our last name your last name is Stone
now only what is his name
it's name is Dolly yes Lisa what is my
name your name is Molly Stone what is my
first name Molly what is my last name
Stone very good very good students aim
now we're going to talk about status and
names we have single and married single
there's single
and married
oh we have the wife and the husband okay
so for formal names we have four men mr.
stone single mr. stone married for women
we have single miss stone married miss
stone also for women single miss stone
and married mrs. stone
now here are some examples miss body
here
mr. Ali oxide and Miss Molly stone miss
Maddie Pierre mr. Ali oxide Miss Molly
stone now here are some examples of
photos mr. Tom Cruise mrs. Hillary
Clinton and Miss Piggy now my formal
name is Miss Molly
Stone Ali what is your formal name boy
Lisa miss Lisa Roberts and money miss my
Pia very good miss Pierre mr. akroy Miss
Roberts
now we're going to learn the alphabet in
English look watch listen a b c d e f g
h i j k l m n o p q r s t u v w x y zit
in america z okay now let's say it
together
a b c d e f g h i j k l m n o p q r s t
u v w x y zit now let's talk about
different kinds of letters
a/e I owe you and sometimes why our
vowels okay
again eh e I owe you why now listen and
practice Lisa what's this
hey Marnie what's this hi Ally what's
this you money what's this
oh and Lisa what's this why good know a
e i o u y these are the vowels now we're
going to talk about consonants okay
these are the consonants b c d e f g h j
k l m n p q r s t v w x zit these are
the consonants now let's practice
Lisa what's this see Li what this is
mari what's this J
Lisa what's this see only what's this
it's Manny
what's this s Lisa what's this
we only what's this wine
Bobby what's this gee Lisa what's this
che and only with this alright
okay one more time a b c d e f g h i j k
l m n o p q r s t u v w X Y Zed now I
want you to listen and write these
letters listen and write listen I'm
right group 1a j k group 2b c d e g p t
v z group 3f l m n s x group 4i y group
5q u w group 6h o r zid now listen and
check your work group 1a
j/k group to b c d e g p t v z group 3 f
l m n f x group for i y group 5 q u w
group 6h o r zit okay in English there
are capital letters letters and small
letters these are also called uppercase
and lowercase
okay these are capital letters small
letters names begin with capital letters
the other letters are small only stone
capital letter capital M small Oh small
L small L small wine capital s small T
small okay capital letters are only here
production spelling now let's practice
spelling names this is what we say
please spell your name please spell your
name capital M o l why
T oh and E please spell your name now
let's practice what is your name my name
is Oksana spell your name capital a and
I capital a K s oh why thank you
what is your first name my first name is
Lisa spell your name
capital L I sa4412b
capital r o be e r t s thank you very
good
introduction to be okay now let's work
on the verb be B now we're going to talk
about a basic basic short an example and
another example
okay now first I I am I am short
I'm I am I'm I'm example I am Molly I am
Molly
short I'm Molly I'm Molly I am I'm I am
Molly I'm Molly okay second one
you are you are short you were your you
are short your example you are
Holly you are
Allie short your ollie
you were ollie you are you were you are
Allie you are only next
he he he is he is short he's he's he is
he's he is tom
he is tom short he's tom he's Tom next
she she is she is short she's she's she
is body
she's Marty next
it is it is short it's it is dolly
it is dolly short it's dolly next
we we are we are short we're we are
we're we are students we are students
short we're students we are we're we are
students
we're students you are you are short
your you are students you are students
short your students you are you were you
are students your students last one they
they are they are short there there they
are students they are students short
their students okay
now students let's look at all of the
examples no I am I'm I am Molly I'm
Molly you are you're you are Ali you
were Ollie he is he's he is Tom he's Tom
she is she's she is Marie she's funny
it is it's it is dolly it's dolly
we are weird
we are students
we're students you are you're you are
students your students they are there
they are students their students now
we're going to practice look at these
sentences and choose the correct verb in
two ways
Lisa two ways you are Lisa okay and
you're Lisa good okay next okay Ally
two ways he's early
next
okay mari
Lisa they are students
secondly they are students
okay Ally I am and I'm and Lisa it is
solely it's dolly
okay very good students now let's look
at these again you are Lisa you are Lisa
he is Ali
she's ollie we are students
we're students they are students they're
students
I am Marie I'm Marty she is Molly she's
Molly
it is dolly it's dolly and listen now
let's look and listen I'm Molly she's
Lisa he's ollie we are teachers they are
assistants
[Music]
okay now we can make questions the
answers are yes or no now here's the
question am i Mali positive answer yes
[Music]
am i Marley yes you are negative answer
no you were not
am i Marley no you're not
am i Mali yes you are okay here's
another one
are you ollie
are you ollie yes I am
are you ollie yes I am or no I'm not
are you ollie
no I'm not are you ollie yes I am okay
here's another question is he
Tom if he Tom yes he yes here's the is
here's the is he he okay is he Tom yes
is he tom no he is not
no he's not no he isn't
is he - um no he's not is he Tom no he
isn't
is he Tom yes he is
okay here comes another question is she
Marty is she money yes she is
is she money yes she is
or no she's not
no she isn't is she money no she's not
is she money no she isn't is she money
yes she is
okay next question is it Dali is it Dali
yes it is
yes it is no it's not or no it isn't is
it Dali no it's not
is it Dali no it isn't is it Dali yes it
is okay
the next one are we
students are we students now this has
two answers yes we are
are we students yes we are
or yes you are
are we students yes you are and of
course we have negative no we're not no
we aren't our weak students no we're not
no we aren't or no you are not no you
aren't
are we students no you're not no you
aren't so again are we students yes we
are are we students no we're not no we
aren't okay another one
are we students yes you are
are we students no you're not no you
aren't okay another question
are you students are you students yes we
are are you students yes we are no we're
not no we aren't are you students yes we
are are you students no we're not no we
aren't
okay last question are they students are
they students answer yes they are are
they students yes they are
and of course negative no they're not no
they aren't
are they students yes they are are they
students no they're not are they
students no they aren't
okay no let's look at all of these again
on the screen questions and answer am i
Molly yes you are no you're not
are you ollie yes I am no I'm not is he
tom yes he is
no he's not no he isn't
is she money yes she is
no she's not no she isn't is it Tolly
yes it is no it's not no it isn't
are we students yes we are no we're not
no we aren't
second question are we students yes you
are no you're not no you aren't
next are you students yes we are no
we're not no we aren't are they students
yes they are no they're not no they
aren't look and listen no let's look and
listen are you Marty yes I am are they
students yes they are
is it Dali no it isn't
[Music]
okay now we're going to talk about
formal introductions formal
introductions this is for people who
have higher status for example doctors
professors etc and this is how you write
it like we saw before it's nice to meet
you name it's nice to meet you too
now here's an example I say professor
Smith this is dr. Jones dr. Jones says
it's nice to meet you professor Smith
and professor Smith says it's nice to
meet you too
professor Smith this is dr. Jones it's
nice to meet you professor Smith it's
nice to meet you too
okay professor doctor now with the help
of our assistants let's practice
now first we have dr. Curie and Princess
Diana now only would you please
introduce them dr. Curie this is
Princess Diana it's nice to meet you dr.
Cruz nice to meet you too princess okay
now we have mother Teresa and President
Bill Clinton and Lisa would you please
introduce them okay while they're soft
this is President Bill Clinton it's nice
to meet your presence it's nice to meet
you too mother Teresa very good now we
have Mustafa Kemal atatürk
and mrs. Clinton now would you introduce
them please my missus Clinton this is
Mustafa Kemal atatürk it is nice to meet
you mister it's nice to meet you too
miss Carrington very good thank you very
much okay now we're going to do in
formal introductions in formal
introductions
these are introductions among friends
this is what we say
mm-hmm this is somebody else so and then
the second person says nice to meet you
and the third person says nice to meet
you too okay now for example Molly says
oli this is Maureen mari says nice to
meet you Ali and Ali says nice to meet
you too
so Ali this is Mari
nice to meet you Ali nice to meet you
too
okay now let's practice a little bit
with our assistants
all right now Ali this is Marie it's
nice to meet you Ali nice to meet you
too
mari this is Lisa nice to meet you Lisa
nice to meet you too now Marie introduce
Lisa to Ali
Lisa this is Ali nice to meet you early
nice to meet you too now Lisa you
introduce Ali to me mr. toan this is Ali
nice to meet you Ali nice to meet you
mrs. Khan very good introduction okay
now you can also introduce yourself
introducing yourself
this is what you say hello I'm that's
the first person the second person says
I'm nice to meet you first person says
nice to meet you too for example I say
Molly hello I'm Molly Lisa I'm Lisa
nice to meet you Molly nice to meet you
too
so hello I'm Molly I'm Lisa
nice to meet you nice to meet you too
now let's practice with our assistants
okay assistants no hello I'm Molly stone
I'm Lisa Roberts nice to meet you nice
to meet you too hello I'm Lisa Robert
I'm Mary Pierre nice to meet you nice to
meet you too hello I'm Mary are hello I
am I Alex very nice to meet you nice to
meet you too I know I might actually
hello I'm Molly stone nice to meet you
nice to meet you too very good
goodbye okay now it's time to learn to
say goodbye and this is how it looks
goodbye short bye see you see you
tomorrow see you later good bye bye see
you see you tomorrow see you later
okay so Ally good bye good one buddy
see you tomorrow please stop bye bye
[Music]
okay now let's do some final review
first a dictation listen and write these
letters listen I'm right
ready okay number one h-e-l-l-o number
two and I see e number three t Oh
number 4 m e e t number five why oh you
now check your work number one h-e-l-l-o
number two and I see e number three T Oh
number 4 m e e t and number five why
oh you hello nice to meet you okay now
listen listen and write these sentences
ready number one
my name is Allie number two it's nice to
meet you number three please spell your
name number four they are students
number five Thank You number one my name
is Allie number two
it's nice to meet you number three
please spell your name number four they
are students number five
thank you finally read this short story
read and answer Lisa Roberts and
marie-pierre our students is he Ali yes
he is his last name is oxide Molly stone
is their teacher okay
now answer the questions listen write
the answers not the questions number one
are Lisa and Murray students number two
what is Ali's last name number three
what is Murray's last name number four
is Molly their teacher number five what
is her last name
now listen to the questions again and
check your answers number one are Lisa
and Marty students yes they are number
two what is Ali's last name it is
actually number three what is Marty's
last name it is pure number four is
Molly their teacher yes she is
and number five what is her last name
Stone
practicing English
[Music]
good morning thanks for waiting for me
no problem
Sam you know who I met yesterday no at
the cafe my old friend Alexei he was my
roommate at university he is from Greece
and his last name is Chris tacos tacos
ah here he is yes he lives in your
building so I asked him to join us he is
waiting for me sure I would like to meet
him too
good morning hi good morning are you
ready yes I am hi hmm well I haven't met
anyone from Greece before is he nice I
think so check that they were good
friends at university Hey
hi Lexi Jack and I would like you to
meet your neighbor this is Sam
she lives in your building Sam this is
Alexi Christakis hello Alexei it's nice
to meet you too when did you come to
Istanbul
I came to Istanbul last week got a new
job at a computer company welcome to our
building oh I'd like you to meet my
mother mother these are my friends this
is Angie I missed Chris tacos it's nice
to meet you welcome to Istanbul Thank
You Angie it's nice to meet you too and
this is my friend Jack he was my
roommate at university it's nice to meet
you jack thank you for being a good
friend to my son thank you very much we
are good friends and this is Sam he
lives in our building Sam it's a
pleasure to meet you how do you like
this building oh it's great we really
like it
well it's very nice to meet all of you
but you'd better get going or you'll
miss your tram
your mother's right we better go bye
mrs. Kristo Sarcos bye have a good day
at work
BYE MOM see you this evening bye
[Music]
Alexi I have a question how do you spell
your first name
well it's pronounced Alexi but it is
felled a lex18 how do you spell it
well my full name is Angela it is
spelled a and GTL a but most people call
me Angie
it is Feld ang ie Lexy my full name is
Samuel my mother is the only person who
calls me Samuel usually means I'm in
trouble
Samuel is spelled s a M u e L but Sam is
much easier it's s a.m. my name is the
easiest and it's just Jack jack3d hi Sam
magic hi Carrie hi Carrie Carrie this is
our new friend Alexi he's from Greece
he lives in Sam's building hi Alexi how
do you like Istanbul
oh it's great it's nice to meet you
Carrie I didn't know I would meet so
many new people you're all very nice
thank you I'm glad you like the city
it's a good place to live
yes I agree I feel very lucky to have
four new friends in only two days come
on it's starting to rain
you